<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Data Science Resources on Laxmikant Soni</title><link>https://laxmikants.github.io/categories/data-science-resources/</link><description>Recent content in Data Science Resources on Laxmikant Soni</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>This work is licensed.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://laxmikants.github.io/categories/data-science-resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Logistic Regression in ML</title><link>https://laxmikants.github.io/post/logistic-regression-in-ml/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://laxmikants.github.io/post/logistic-regression-in-ml/</guid><description>HUGOMORE42
Logistic Regression
Introduction
Logistic regression is a classification algorithm used to assign
observations to a discrete set of classes. Unlike linear regression
which outputs continuous number values, logistic regression transforms
its output using the logistic sigmoid function to return a probability
value which can then be mapped to two or more discrete classes.
Comparison to linear regression
Given data on time spent studying and exam scores. linear_regression
and logistic regression can predict different things:</description></item><item><title>Regression in ML</title><link>https://laxmikants.github.io/post/regression-in-ml/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://laxmikants.github.io/post/regression-in-ml/</guid><description>HUGOMORE42
Definition
A linear equation that models a function such that if we give any x to it, it will predict a value y , where both x and y are input and output variables respectively. These are numerical and continous values.
It is the most simple and well known algorithm used in machine learning.
Flowchart
The above Flowchart represents that we choose our training set, feed it to an algorithm, it will learn the patterns and will output a function called Hypothesis function &#39;H(x)&#39;.</description></item><item><title>Proportion test in R</title><link>https://laxmikants.github.io/post/proportion-test-in-r/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://laxmikants.github.io/post/proportion-test-in-r/</guid><description>Hypothesis testing and P-values: Suppose our data are such that out of a sample of n=180 trials (=students), 120 resulted in successes (=indicated that they are in favor of lowering the drinking age to below 18 years). Our goal is to test hypotheses and construct confidence intervals about the true (unknown) proportion of successes (proportion of students who are in favor of lowering the drinking age) in the entire population. Let’s lookat a two-sided test of the (alternative) hypothesis that the true proportion is different from 0.</description></item></channel></rss>