<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Statistical Comparison on Laxmikant Soni</title><link>https://laxmikants.github.io/categories/statistical-comparison/</link><description>Recent content in Statistical Comparison on Laxmikant Soni</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>This work is licensed.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://laxmikants.github.io/categories/statistical-comparison/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Science Process</title><link>https://laxmikants.github.io/post/data-science-process/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://laxmikants.github.io/post/data-science-process/</guid><description>HUGOMORE42 Data Science Process?
A Data science process is a life cycle process for delivering a data science project that helps a data consumer to gain insights from the data.
It involves the following steps. They are as follows:
Describing the data problem by asking the right questions
Collecting the data
Transforming the raw data in to the format required applying Data munging techniques
Exploring Data by using EDA techniques
Advanced Exploratory data analysis.</description></item><item><title>Time-Series Forecasting</title><link>https://laxmikants.github.io/post/time-series-data-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://laxmikants.github.io/post/time-series-data-analysis/</guid><description>HUGOMORE42 What is time series?
A time series is a series of observations collected at some time intervals.
Time is an important component here. The observations collected are dependent on the time at which it is collected.
The sale items in a retail store like Walmart will be a time series. The sale could be at daily level or weekly level.
The number of people flying from Bangalore to delhi on daily basis is a time series.</description></item><item><title>Decision Trees</title><link>https://laxmikants.github.io/post/decision-trees-in-ml/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://laxmikants.github.io/post/decision-trees-in-ml/</guid><description>HUGOMORE42 Decision trees
Decision trees area tree-like tool which can be used to represent a cause and its effect.
In Machine Learning Decision trees are a type of Supervised machine learning where data
is split according to given parameter while constructing a tree to solve a given problem.
In decision tree there is a predictor variable and target variable or the desired output.
The predictor variable could be anything such as technical indicators etc and the target
variable could be desired output for example whether to invest in a given financial security or not.</description></item><item><title>Data Science Terminology</title><link>https://laxmikants.github.io/post/data-science-terminology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://laxmikants.github.io/post/data-science-terminology/</guid><description>HUGOMORE42 Data Science Terminology
Based upon personal experience, research, and various industry experts’ advice, someone delving
into the art of data science should take every opportunity to understand and gain experience as well as proficiency with the following list of common data science terms:
Statistical population
Statistical population as a recordset (or a set of records). This set or group of records will be of similar items or events that are of interest to the data scientist for some experiment.</description></item><item><title>Big Data Analytics</title><link>https://laxmikants.github.io/post/what-is-big-data-analytics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://laxmikants.github.io/post/what-is-big-data-analytics/</guid><description>Big-data and Analytics: Do we know how we can reach at a decision based on mobile data or computer data or Aadhar number? How to find that the new accounts that are opened in the Pradhan Mantri&amp;rsquo;s Jan Dhan Yojana does not have enough money ?
How does company know that their brand is making consumers happy or not? OK, this works based on the Big-data Analytics. Lets us understand what this is, When we call it Big Data Analytics then this directly links us i.</description></item></channel></rss>